,UUID4,ToposText_ID,Place_Name,Reference,Lat,Long,Book,Chapter,Paragraph,Text,Text_ner
85,207c579f-b55c-4e95-9ea9-fba4927c40e8,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.75.1,30.0,74.0,2,75,1.0,"Similarly it is reported that at the town of Syene, 5000 stades South of Alexandria, at noon in midsummer no shadow is cast, and that in a well made for the sake of testing this the light reaches to the bottom, clearly showing that the sun is vertically above that place at the time; and this is stated in the writings of Onesicritus also to occur at the same time in India South of the river Hypasis. It is also stated that in the Cave-dwellers' city of Berenice, and 4820 stades away at the town of Ptolemais in the same tribe, which was founded on the shore of the Red Sea for the earliest elephant hunts, the same thing occurs 45 days before and 45 days after midsummer, and during that period of 90 days the shadows are thrown southward. Again in Meroe — this is an inhabited island in the river Nile 5000 stades from Syene, and is the capital of the Aethiopian race — the shadows disappear twice a year, when the sun is in the 18th degree of Taurus and in the 14th of Leo. There is a mountain named Maleus in the Indian tribe of the Oretes, near which shadows are thrown southward in summer and northward in winter; the northern constellation is visible there on only 15 nights. Also in India at the well-known port of Patala the sun rises on the right and shadows fall southward. It was noticed when Alexander was staying at this place that the Great and Little Bears were visible only in the early part of the night. Alexander's guide Onesicritus wrote that this constellation is not visible at the places in India where there are no shadows, and that these places are called Shadeless, and no reckoning is kept of the hours there. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99636984, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 45, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9206566, 'word': 'Alexandria', 'start': 73, 'end': 83}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.92516124, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 322, 'end': 333}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9750353, 'word': 'India', 'start': 368, 'end': 373}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.89377725, 'word': 'Hypasis', 'start': 393, 'end': 400}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.661921, 'word': 'Cave - dwellers', 'start': 432, 'end': 445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98890007, 'word': 'Berenice', 'start': 455, 'end': 463}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99032825, 'word': 'Ptolemais', 'start': 501, 'end': 510}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9764259, 'word': 'Red Sea', 'start': 568, 'end': 575}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9597429, 'word': 'Meroe', 'start': 752, 'end': 757}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9352231, 'word': 'Nile', 'start': 801, 'end': 805}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9778486, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 823, 'end': 828}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8297264, 'word': 'Aethiopian', 'start': 856, 'end': 866}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9132286, 'word': 'Taurus', 'start': 948, 'end': 954}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8875982, 'word': 'Leo', 'start': 974, 'end': 977}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98561734, 'word': 'Maleus', 'start': 1005, 'end': 1011}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.84965897, 'word': 'Indian', 'start': 1019, 'end': 1025}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7138374, 'word': 'Oretes', 'start': 1039, 'end': 1045}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9969561, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1193, 'end': 1198}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9948095, 'word': 'Patala', 'start': 1225, 'end': 1231}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.96130216, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1307, 'end': 1316}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5078376, 'word': 'Great', 'start': 1352, 'end': 1357}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5649371, 'word': 'Little', 'start': 1362, 'end': 1368}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.5485065, 'word': 'Bears', 'start': 1369, 'end': 1374}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9506092, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1425, 'end': 1434}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.93376637, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1454}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9696175, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1517, 'end': 1522}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.61309075, 'word': 'Shadeless', 'start': 1584, 'end': 1593}]"
92,b9f04f79-5470-40cb-bfe6-2db3fdac6eb4,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.75.1,30.0,74.0,2,75,1.0,"Similarly it is reported that at the town of Syene, 5000 stades South of Alexandria, at noon in midsummer no shadow is cast, and that in a well made for the sake of testing this the light reaches to the bottom, clearly showing that the sun is vertically above that place at the time; and this is stated in the writings of Onesicritus also to occur at the same time in India South of the river Hypasis. It is also stated that in the Cave-dwellers' city of Berenice, and 4820 stades away at the town of Ptolemais in the same tribe, which was founded on the shore of the Red Sea for the earliest elephant hunts, the same thing occurs 45 days before and 45 days after midsummer, and during that period of 90 days the shadows are thrown southward. Again in Meroe — this is an inhabited island in the river Nile 5000 stades from Syene, and is the capital of the Aethiopian race — the shadows disappear twice a year, when the sun is in the 18th degree of Taurus and in the 14th of Leo. There is a mountain named Maleus in the Indian tribe of the Oretes, near which shadows are thrown southward in summer and northward in winter; the northern constellation is visible there on only 15 nights. Also in India at the well-known port of Patala the sun rises on the right and shadows fall southward. It was noticed when Alexander was staying at this place that the Great and Little Bears were visible only in the early part of the night. Alexander's guide Onesicritus wrote that this constellation is not visible at the places in India where there are no shadows, and that these places are called Shadeless, and no reckoning is kept of the hours there. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99636984, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 45, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9206566, 'word': 'Alexandria', 'start': 73, 'end': 83}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.92516124, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 322, 'end': 333}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9750353, 'word': 'India', 'start': 368, 'end': 373}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.89377725, 'word': 'Hypasis', 'start': 393, 'end': 400}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.661921, 'word': 'Cave - dwellers', 'start': 432, 'end': 445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98890007, 'word': 'Berenice', 'start': 455, 'end': 463}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99032825, 'word': 'Ptolemais', 'start': 501, 'end': 510}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9764259, 'word': 'Red Sea', 'start': 568, 'end': 575}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9597429, 'word': 'Meroe', 'start': 752, 'end': 757}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9352231, 'word': 'Nile', 'start': 801, 'end': 805}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9778486, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 823, 'end': 828}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8297264, 'word': 'Aethiopian', 'start': 856, 'end': 866}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9132286, 'word': 'Taurus', 'start': 948, 'end': 954}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8875982, 'word': 'Leo', 'start': 974, 'end': 977}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98561734, 'word': 'Maleus', 'start': 1005, 'end': 1011}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.84965897, 'word': 'Indian', 'start': 1019, 'end': 1025}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7138374, 'word': 'Oretes', 'start': 1039, 'end': 1045}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9969561, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1193, 'end': 1198}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9948095, 'word': 'Patala', 'start': 1225, 'end': 1231}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.96130216, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1307, 'end': 1316}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5078376, 'word': 'Great', 'start': 1352, 'end': 1357}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5649371, 'word': 'Little', 'start': 1362, 'end': 1368}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.5485065, 'word': 'Bears', 'start': 1369, 'end': 1374}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9506092, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1425, 'end': 1434}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.93376637, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1454}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9696175, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1517, 'end': 1522}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.61309075, 'word': 'Shadeless', 'start': 1584, 'end': 1593}]"
93,c89bc846-01e4-4da1-8dfc-b8fff343ee8b,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.75.1,30.0,74.0,2,75,1.0,"Similarly it is reported that at the town of Syene, 5000 stades South of Alexandria, at noon in midsummer no shadow is cast, and that in a well made for the sake of testing this the light reaches to the bottom, clearly showing that the sun is vertically above that place at the time; and this is stated in the writings of Onesicritus also to occur at the same time in India South of the river Hypasis. It is also stated that in the Cave-dwellers' city of Berenice, and 4820 stades away at the town of Ptolemais in the same tribe, which was founded on the shore of the Red Sea for the earliest elephant hunts, the same thing occurs 45 days before and 45 days after midsummer, and during that period of 90 days the shadows are thrown southward. Again in Meroe — this is an inhabited island in the river Nile 5000 stades from Syene, and is the capital of the Aethiopian race — the shadows disappear twice a year, when the sun is in the 18th degree of Taurus and in the 14th of Leo. There is a mountain named Maleus in the Indian tribe of the Oretes, near which shadows are thrown southward in summer and northward in winter; the northern constellation is visible there on only 15 nights. Also in India at the well-known port of Patala the sun rises on the right and shadows fall southward. It was noticed when Alexander was staying at this place that the Great and Little Bears were visible only in the early part of the night. Alexander's guide Onesicritus wrote that this constellation is not visible at the places in India where there are no shadows, and that these places are called Shadeless, and no reckoning is kept of the hours there. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99636984, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 45, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9206566, 'word': 'Alexandria', 'start': 73, 'end': 83}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.92516124, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 322, 'end': 333}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9750353, 'word': 'India', 'start': 368, 'end': 373}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.89377725, 'word': 'Hypasis', 'start': 393, 'end': 400}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.661921, 'word': 'Cave - dwellers', 'start': 432, 'end': 445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98890007, 'word': 'Berenice', 'start': 455, 'end': 463}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99032825, 'word': 'Ptolemais', 'start': 501, 'end': 510}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9764259, 'word': 'Red Sea', 'start': 568, 'end': 575}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9597429, 'word': 'Meroe', 'start': 752, 'end': 757}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9352231, 'word': 'Nile', 'start': 801, 'end': 805}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9778486, 'word': 'Syene', 'start': 823, 'end': 828}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8297264, 'word': 'Aethiopian', 'start': 856, 'end': 866}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9132286, 'word': 'Taurus', 'start': 948, 'end': 954}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8875982, 'word': 'Leo', 'start': 974, 'end': 977}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98561734, 'word': 'Maleus', 'start': 1005, 'end': 1011}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.84965897, 'word': 'Indian', 'start': 1019, 'end': 1025}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7138374, 'word': 'Oretes', 'start': 1039, 'end': 1045}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9969561, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1193, 'end': 1198}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9948095, 'word': 'Patala', 'start': 1225, 'end': 1231}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.96130216, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1307, 'end': 1316}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5078376, 'word': 'Great', 'start': 1352, 'end': 1357}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5649371, 'word': 'Little', 'start': 1362, 'end': 1368}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.5485065, 'word': 'Bears', 'start': 1369, 'end': 1374}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9506092, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 1425, 'end': 1434}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.93376637, 'word': 'Onesicritus', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1454}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9696175, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1517, 'end': 1522}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.61309075, 'word': 'Shadeless', 'start': 1584, 'end': 1593}]"
218,8f9930fa-cdb7-4335-8de7-9d373c19a6ca,https://topostext.org/place/254683WInd,Indus,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.98.1,25.4487,68.3192,2,98,1.0,"Near the town of Harpasa in Asia stands a jagged rock that can be moved with one finger, but that also resists a push made with the whole body. On the peninsula of the Taurians in the state of Parasinum there is some earth which heals all wounds. But in the neighbourhood of Assos in the Troad a stone is produced that causes all bodies to waste away; it is called the Flesh-eater. There are two mountains near the river Indus, the nature of one of which is to hold all iron and that of the other to reject it; consequently if a man has nails in his shoes, on one of the mountains at each step he is unable to tear his foot away from the ground and on the other he cannot set it down on the ground. It is recorded that at Locri and Croton there has never been a plague or earthquake, and that in Lycia an earthquake is always followed by forty days' fine weather. Corn sown in the Arpi district does not come up, and at Mycian Altars in the district of Veii and at Tusculum and in the Ciminian Forest there are places where stakes driven into the ground cannot be pulled out. Hay grown in the Crustuminum district is noxious on the spot but healthy when conveyed elsewhere. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.999539, 'word': 'Harpasa', 'start': 17, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9976751, 'word': 'Asia', 'start': 28, 'end': 32}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9736084, 'word': 'Taurians', 'start': 168, 'end': 176}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98296577, 'word': 'Parasinum', 'start': 193, 'end': 202}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9953453, 'word': 'Assos', 'start': 275, 'end': 280}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9445782, 'word': 'Troad', 'start': 288, 'end': 293}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98201984, 'word': 'Indus', 'start': 421, 'end': 426}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9975545, 'word': 'Locri', 'start': 722, 'end': 727}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9958484, 'word': 'Croton', 'start': 732, 'end': 738}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99802303, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 796, 'end': 801}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9941385, 'word': 'Arpi', 'start': 881, 'end': 885}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9947519, 'word': 'Mycian Altars', 'start': 920, 'end': 933}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96036154, 'word': 'Veii', 'start': 953, 'end': 957}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9961726, 'word': 'Tusculum', 'start': 965, 'end': 973}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9953737, 'word': 'Ciminian Forest', 'start': 985, 'end': 1000}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9914852, 'word': 'Crustuminum', 'start': 1093, 'end': 1104}]"
326,f0a4eea3-39df-47f6-a633-a2bac50648d8,https://topostext.org/place/340670RBac,Bactria,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.110.1,36.768,66.901,2,110,1.0,"But among mountain marvels — Etna always glows at night, and supplies its fires with fuel sufficient for a vast period, though in winter cloaked with snow and covering its output of ashes with hoar frost. Nor does nature's wrath employ Mount Etna only to threaten the lands with conflagration. Mount Chimaera in the country of Phaselis is on fire, and indeed burns with a flame that does not die by day or night; Ctesias of Cnidos states that water increases its fire but earth or dung puts it out. Also the Mountains of Hephaestus in Lycia flare up when touched with a flaming torch, and so violently that even the stones of the rivers and the sands actually under water glow; and rain only serves to feed this fire. They say that if somebody lights a stick at it and draws a furrow with the stick, streams of fire follow it. At Cophantium in Bactria a coil of flame blazes in the night, and the same in Media and in Sittacene the frontier of Persia: indeed at the White Tower at Susa it does so from fifteen smoke-holes, from the largest in the daytime also. The Babylonian Plain sends a blaze out of a sort of pool an acre in extent; also near Mount Hesperus in Ethiopia the plains shine at night like stars. Likewise in the territory of Megalopolis. For if that agreeable Bowl of Nymphaeus, which does not scorch the foliage of the thick wood above it and though near a cold stream is always glowing hot, ceases to flow, it portends horrors to its neighbours in the town of Apollonia, as Theopompus has recorded. It is augmented by rain, and sends forth asphalt to mingle with that unappetizing stream, which even without this is more liquid than ordinary asphalt. But who would be surprised by these things? During the Allies' War Holy Island and Lipari among the Aeolian Islands near Italy burnt in mid sea for several days, as did the sea itself, till a deputation from the senate performed a propitiatory ceremony. Nevertheless the largest volcanic blaze is that of the ridge in Ethiopia called the Gods' Carriage, which discharges flames that glow with truly solar heat. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.87196684, 'word': 'Etna', 'start': 29, 'end': 33}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98362523, 'word': 'Mount Etna', 'start': 236, 'end': 246}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9860288, 'word': 'Mount Chimaera', 'start': 294, 'end': 308}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96671474, 'word': 'Phaselis', 'start': 327, 'end': 335}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9795568, 'word': 'Ctesias', 'start': 413, 'end': 420}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.94416565, 'word': 'Cnidos', 'start': 424, 'end': 430}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98719245, 'word': 'Mountains of Hephaestus', 'start': 508, 'end': 531}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98735166, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 535, 'end': 540}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9395978, 'word': 'Cophantium', 'start': 830, 'end': 840}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9702799, 'word': 'Bactria', 'start': 844, 'end': 851}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9604738, 'word': 'Media', 'start': 905, 'end': 910}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9724129, 'word': 'Sittacene', 'start': 918, 'end': 927}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96222985, 'word': 'Persia', 'start': 944, 'end': 950}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9800876, 'word': 'White Tower', 'start': 966, 'end': 977}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9682956, 'word': 'Susa', 'start': 981, 'end': 985}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9847475, 'word': 'Babylonian Plain', 'start': 1065, 'end': 1081}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9925585, 'word': 'Mount Hesperus', 'start': 1147, 'end': 1161}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99229455, 'word': 'Ethiopia', 'start': 1165, 'end': 1173}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9769917, 'word': 'Megalopolis', 'start': 1241, 'end': 1252}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96947193, 'word': 'Bowl of Nymphaeus', 'start': 1276, 'end': 1293}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.926464, 'word': 'Apollonia', 'start': 1478, 'end': 1487}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.83977664, 'word': 'Theopompus', 'start': 1492, 'end': 1502}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.87341046, 'word': ""Allies ' War Holy"", 'start': 1724, 'end': 1740}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8985071, 'word': 'Island', 'start': 1741, 'end': 1747}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9068087, 'word': 'Lipari', 'start': 1752, 'end': 1758}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.94898516, 'word': 'Aeolian Islands', 'start': 1769, 'end': 1784}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9703644, 'word': 'Italy', 'start': 1790, 'end': 1795}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9438341, 'word': 'Ethiopia', 'start': 1987, 'end': 1995}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.8479393, 'word': ""Gods ' Carriage"", 'start': 2007, 'end': 2021}]"
343,e15115b9-70a7-4578-a57f-2bf035545adb,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.112.1,30.0,74.0,2,112,1.0,"Our own portion of the earth, which is my subject, swims as it were in the ocean by which, as we have said, it is surrounded; its longest extent is from East to West, i.e. from India to the Pillars consecrated to Hercules at Cadiz, a distance of 8,568 miles according to Artemidorus, but 9,818 according to Isidore. Artemidorus adds in addition from Cadiz round the Sacred Promontory to Artabrum promontory, the longest projection of the coast of Spain, 890 1/2 miles. The measurement runs by a double route; from the river Ganges and its mouth where it flows into the Eastern Ocean, through India and Parthyene to the Syrian city of Myriandrus situated on the Issic gulf 5,215, from there by the shortest sea-route to the island of Cyprus, from Patara in Lycia to Rhodes, to the island of Astypalaea in the Carpathian Sea, to Taenarus in Laconia, Lilybaion in Sicily, Caralis in Sardinia, 213, thence to Cadiz 1,250, the total distance from the Eastern Sea making 8,568. Another route, which is more certain, extends mainly overland from the Ganges to the river Euphrates 5,169, thence to Mazaca in Cappadocia 244, thence through Phrygia and Caria to Ephesus 499, from Ephesus across the Aegean Sea to Delos 200, to the Isthmus 202 1/2, thence by land and the Alcyonian Sea and the Gulf of Corinth to Patras in the Peloponnese 102 1/2, to Leucas 87 1/2, to Corcyra ditto, to Acroceraunia 82 1/2, to Brindisi 87 1/2, to Rome 360, across the Alps to the village of Scingomagum 518, through Gallia to the Pyrenees at Illiberis 456, to the Ocean and the coast of Spain 832, across to Cadiz 7 1/2 — which figures by Artemidorus's calculation make 8,995 miles. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7412269, 'word': 'East', 'start': 153, 'end': 157}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.77896315, 'word': 'West', 'start': 161, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9901855, 'word': 'India', 'start': 177, 'end': 182}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.981185, 'word': 'Pillars', 'start': 190, 'end': 197}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6513607, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 213, 'end': 221}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9983041, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 225, 'end': 230}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99825233, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 271, 'end': 282}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9981376, 'word': 'Isidore', 'start': 307, 'end': 314}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99760133, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 316, 'end': 327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99863917, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 350, 'end': 355}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952378, 'word': 'Sacred Promontory', 'start': 366, 'end': 383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99757296, 'word': 'Artabrum', 'start': 387, 'end': 395}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9771263, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 447, 'end': 452}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99382377, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 524, 'end': 530}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99455774, 'word': 'Eastern Ocean', 'start': 569, 'end': 582}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9964535, 'word': 'India', 'start': 592, 'end': 597}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9974421, 'word': 'Parthyene', 'start': 602, 'end': 611}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7181697, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 619, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9957962, 'word': 'Myriandrus', 'start': 634, 'end': 644}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99472, 'word': 'Issic', 'start': 661, 'end': 666}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9846884, 'word': 'Cyprus', 'start': 733, 'end': 739}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99746203, 'word': 'Patara', 'start': 746, 'end': 752}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99605405, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 756, 'end': 761}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950653, 'word': 'Rhodes', 'start': 765, 'end': 771}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950871, 'word': 'Astypalaea', 'start': 790, 'end': 800}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952965, 'word': 'Carpathian Sea', 'start': 808, 'end': 822}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9977053, 'word': 'Taenarus', 'start': 827, 'end': 835}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973834, 'word': 'Laconia', 'start': 839, 'end': 846}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99835664, 'word': 'Lilybaion', 'start': 848, 'end': 857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9965731, 'word': 'Sicily', 'start': 861, 'end': 867}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9982034, 'word': 'Caralis', 'start': 869, 'end': 876}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973908, 'word': 'Sardinia', 'start': 880, 'end': 888}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9985423, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 905, 'end': 910}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99497855, 'word': 'Eastern Sea', 'start': 946, 'end': 957}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9984516, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 1043, 'end': 1049}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99564904, 'word': 'Euphrates', 'start': 1063, 'end': 1072}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99918693, 'word': 'Mazaca', 'start': 1090, 'end': 1096}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.998516, 'word': 'Cappadocia', 'start': 1100, 'end': 1110}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99844235, 'word': 'Phrygia', 'start': 1131, 'end': 1138}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9980102, 'word': 'Caria', 'start': 1143, 'end': 1148}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99822694, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1152, 'end': 1159}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99890864, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1170, 'end': 1177}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99849844, 'word': 'Aegean Sea', 'start': 1189, 'end': 1199}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99842453, 'word': 'Delos', 'start': 1203, 'end': 1208}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99730116, 'word': 'Isthmus', 'start': 1221, 'end': 1228}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99797475, 'word': 'Alcyonian Sea', 'start': 1261, 'end': 1274}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9968625, 'word': 'Gulf of Corinth', 'start': 1283, 'end': 1298}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99786973, 'word': 'Patras', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1308}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950677, 'word': 'Peloponnese', 'start': 1316, 'end': 1327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99770325, 'word': 'Leucas', 'start': 1340, 'end': 1346}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99699163, 'word': 'Corcyra', 'start': 1358, 'end': 1365}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9966653, 'word': 'Acroceraunia', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1388}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99693537, 'word': 'Brindisi', 'start': 1400, 'end': 1408}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9930004, 'word': 'Rome', 'start': 1420, 'end': 1424}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9881126, 'word': 'Alps', 'start': 1441, 'end': 1445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99629056, 'word': 'Scingomagum', 'start': 1464, 'end': 1475}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9877423, 'word': 'Gallia', 'start': 1489, 'end': 1495}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99149173, 'word': 'Pyrenees', 'start': 1503, 'end': 1511}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9932939, 'word': 'Illiberis', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1524}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9776768, 'word': 'Ocean', 'start': 1537, 'end': 1542}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9586628, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 1560, 'end': 1565}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99361765, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 1581, 'end': 1586}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.988962, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 1612, 'end': 1623}]"
348,b80a6b84-d617-482f-a054-bbf20bf3e7bf,https://topostext.org/place/38898WGan,Ganges,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.112.1,23.7818,89.8009,2,112,1.0,"Our own portion of the earth, which is my subject, swims as it were in the ocean by which, as we have said, it is surrounded; its longest extent is from East to West, i.e. from India to the Pillars consecrated to Hercules at Cadiz, a distance of 8,568 miles according to Artemidorus, but 9,818 according to Isidore. Artemidorus adds in addition from Cadiz round the Sacred Promontory to Artabrum promontory, the longest projection of the coast of Spain, 890 1/2 miles. The measurement runs by a double route; from the river Ganges and its mouth where it flows into the Eastern Ocean, through India and Parthyene to the Syrian city of Myriandrus situated on the Issic gulf 5,215, from there by the shortest sea-route to the island of Cyprus, from Patara in Lycia to Rhodes, to the island of Astypalaea in the Carpathian Sea, to Taenarus in Laconia, Lilybaion in Sicily, Caralis in Sardinia, 213, thence to Cadiz 1,250, the total distance from the Eastern Sea making 8,568. Another route, which is more certain, extends mainly overland from the Ganges to the river Euphrates 5,169, thence to Mazaca in Cappadocia 244, thence through Phrygia and Caria to Ephesus 499, from Ephesus across the Aegean Sea to Delos 200, to the Isthmus 202 1/2, thence by land and the Alcyonian Sea and the Gulf of Corinth to Patras in the Peloponnese 102 1/2, to Leucas 87 1/2, to Corcyra ditto, to Acroceraunia 82 1/2, to Brindisi 87 1/2, to Rome 360, across the Alps to the village of Scingomagum 518, through Gallia to the Pyrenees at Illiberis 456, to the Ocean and the coast of Spain 832, across to Cadiz 7 1/2 — which figures by Artemidorus's calculation make 8,995 miles. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7412269, 'word': 'East', 'start': 153, 'end': 157}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.77896315, 'word': 'West', 'start': 161, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9901855, 'word': 'India', 'start': 177, 'end': 182}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.981185, 'word': 'Pillars', 'start': 190, 'end': 197}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6513607, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 213, 'end': 221}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9983041, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 225, 'end': 230}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99825233, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 271, 'end': 282}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9981376, 'word': 'Isidore', 'start': 307, 'end': 314}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99760133, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 316, 'end': 327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99863917, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 350, 'end': 355}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952378, 'word': 'Sacred Promontory', 'start': 366, 'end': 383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99757296, 'word': 'Artabrum', 'start': 387, 'end': 395}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9771263, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 447, 'end': 452}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99382377, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 524, 'end': 530}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99455774, 'word': 'Eastern Ocean', 'start': 569, 'end': 582}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9964535, 'word': 'India', 'start': 592, 'end': 597}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9974421, 'word': 'Parthyene', 'start': 602, 'end': 611}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7181697, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 619, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9957962, 'word': 'Myriandrus', 'start': 634, 'end': 644}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99472, 'word': 'Issic', 'start': 661, 'end': 666}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9846884, 'word': 'Cyprus', 'start': 733, 'end': 739}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99746203, 'word': 'Patara', 'start': 746, 'end': 752}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99605405, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 756, 'end': 761}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950653, 'word': 'Rhodes', 'start': 765, 'end': 771}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950871, 'word': 'Astypalaea', 'start': 790, 'end': 800}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952965, 'word': 'Carpathian Sea', 'start': 808, 'end': 822}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9977053, 'word': 'Taenarus', 'start': 827, 'end': 835}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973834, 'word': 'Laconia', 'start': 839, 'end': 846}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99835664, 'word': 'Lilybaion', 'start': 848, 'end': 857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9965731, 'word': 'Sicily', 'start': 861, 'end': 867}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9982034, 'word': 'Caralis', 'start': 869, 'end': 876}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973908, 'word': 'Sardinia', 'start': 880, 'end': 888}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9985423, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 905, 'end': 910}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99497855, 'word': 'Eastern Sea', 'start': 946, 'end': 957}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9984516, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 1043, 'end': 1049}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99564904, 'word': 'Euphrates', 'start': 1063, 'end': 1072}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99918693, 'word': 'Mazaca', 'start': 1090, 'end': 1096}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.998516, 'word': 'Cappadocia', 'start': 1100, 'end': 1110}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99844235, 'word': 'Phrygia', 'start': 1131, 'end': 1138}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9980102, 'word': 'Caria', 'start': 1143, 'end': 1148}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99822694, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1152, 'end': 1159}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99890864, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1170, 'end': 1177}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99849844, 'word': 'Aegean Sea', 'start': 1189, 'end': 1199}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99842453, 'word': 'Delos', 'start': 1203, 'end': 1208}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99730116, 'word': 'Isthmus', 'start': 1221, 'end': 1228}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99797475, 'word': 'Alcyonian Sea', 'start': 1261, 'end': 1274}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9968625, 'word': 'Gulf of Corinth', 'start': 1283, 'end': 1298}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99786973, 'word': 'Patras', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1308}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950677, 'word': 'Peloponnese', 'start': 1316, 'end': 1327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99770325, 'word': 'Leucas', 'start': 1340, 'end': 1346}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99699163, 'word': 'Corcyra', 'start': 1358, 'end': 1365}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9966653, 'word': 'Acroceraunia', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1388}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99693537, 'word': 'Brindisi', 'start': 1400, 'end': 1408}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9930004, 'word': 'Rome', 'start': 1420, 'end': 1424}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9881126, 'word': 'Alps', 'start': 1441, 'end': 1445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99629056, 'word': 'Scingomagum', 'start': 1464, 'end': 1475}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9877423, 'word': 'Gallia', 'start': 1489, 'end': 1495}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99149173, 'word': 'Pyrenees', 'start': 1503, 'end': 1511}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9932939, 'word': 'Illiberis', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1524}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9776768, 'word': 'Ocean', 'start': 1537, 'end': 1542}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9586628, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 1560, 'end': 1565}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99361765, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 1581, 'end': 1586}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.988962, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 1612, 'end': 1623}]"
349,2d52b3d4-31e0-4296-85b0-f21c671b3a0c,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.112.1,30.0,74.0,2,112,1.0,"Our own portion of the earth, which is my subject, swims as it were in the ocean by which, as we have said, it is surrounded; its longest extent is from East to West, i.e. from India to the Pillars consecrated to Hercules at Cadiz, a distance of 8,568 miles according to Artemidorus, but 9,818 according to Isidore. Artemidorus adds in addition from Cadiz round the Sacred Promontory to Artabrum promontory, the longest projection of the coast of Spain, 890 1/2 miles. The measurement runs by a double route; from the river Ganges and its mouth where it flows into the Eastern Ocean, through India and Parthyene to the Syrian city of Myriandrus situated on the Issic gulf 5,215, from there by the shortest sea-route to the island of Cyprus, from Patara in Lycia to Rhodes, to the island of Astypalaea in the Carpathian Sea, to Taenarus in Laconia, Lilybaion in Sicily, Caralis in Sardinia, 213, thence to Cadiz 1,250, the total distance from the Eastern Sea making 8,568. Another route, which is more certain, extends mainly overland from the Ganges to the river Euphrates 5,169, thence to Mazaca in Cappadocia 244, thence through Phrygia and Caria to Ephesus 499, from Ephesus across the Aegean Sea to Delos 200, to the Isthmus 202 1/2, thence by land and the Alcyonian Sea and the Gulf of Corinth to Patras in the Peloponnese 102 1/2, to Leucas 87 1/2, to Corcyra ditto, to Acroceraunia 82 1/2, to Brindisi 87 1/2, to Rome 360, across the Alps to the village of Scingomagum 518, through Gallia to the Pyrenees at Illiberis 456, to the Ocean and the coast of Spain 832, across to Cadiz 7 1/2 — which figures by Artemidorus's calculation make 8,995 miles. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7412269, 'word': 'East', 'start': 153, 'end': 157}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.77896315, 'word': 'West', 'start': 161, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9901855, 'word': 'India', 'start': 177, 'end': 182}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.981185, 'word': 'Pillars', 'start': 190, 'end': 197}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6513607, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 213, 'end': 221}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9983041, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 225, 'end': 230}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99825233, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 271, 'end': 282}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9981376, 'word': 'Isidore', 'start': 307, 'end': 314}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99760133, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 316, 'end': 327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99863917, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 350, 'end': 355}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952378, 'word': 'Sacred Promontory', 'start': 366, 'end': 383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99757296, 'word': 'Artabrum', 'start': 387, 'end': 395}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9771263, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 447, 'end': 452}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99382377, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 524, 'end': 530}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99455774, 'word': 'Eastern Ocean', 'start': 569, 'end': 582}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9964535, 'word': 'India', 'start': 592, 'end': 597}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9974421, 'word': 'Parthyene', 'start': 602, 'end': 611}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7181697, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 619, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9957962, 'word': 'Myriandrus', 'start': 634, 'end': 644}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99472, 'word': 'Issic', 'start': 661, 'end': 666}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9846884, 'word': 'Cyprus', 'start': 733, 'end': 739}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99746203, 'word': 'Patara', 'start': 746, 'end': 752}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99605405, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 756, 'end': 761}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950653, 'word': 'Rhodes', 'start': 765, 'end': 771}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950871, 'word': 'Astypalaea', 'start': 790, 'end': 800}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952965, 'word': 'Carpathian Sea', 'start': 808, 'end': 822}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9977053, 'word': 'Taenarus', 'start': 827, 'end': 835}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973834, 'word': 'Laconia', 'start': 839, 'end': 846}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99835664, 'word': 'Lilybaion', 'start': 848, 'end': 857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9965731, 'word': 'Sicily', 'start': 861, 'end': 867}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9982034, 'word': 'Caralis', 'start': 869, 'end': 876}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973908, 'word': 'Sardinia', 'start': 880, 'end': 888}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9985423, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 905, 'end': 910}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99497855, 'word': 'Eastern Sea', 'start': 946, 'end': 957}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9984516, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 1043, 'end': 1049}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99564904, 'word': 'Euphrates', 'start': 1063, 'end': 1072}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99918693, 'word': 'Mazaca', 'start': 1090, 'end': 1096}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.998516, 'word': 'Cappadocia', 'start': 1100, 'end': 1110}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99844235, 'word': 'Phrygia', 'start': 1131, 'end': 1138}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9980102, 'word': 'Caria', 'start': 1143, 'end': 1148}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99822694, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1152, 'end': 1159}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99890864, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1170, 'end': 1177}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99849844, 'word': 'Aegean Sea', 'start': 1189, 'end': 1199}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99842453, 'word': 'Delos', 'start': 1203, 'end': 1208}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99730116, 'word': 'Isthmus', 'start': 1221, 'end': 1228}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99797475, 'word': 'Alcyonian Sea', 'start': 1261, 'end': 1274}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9968625, 'word': 'Gulf of Corinth', 'start': 1283, 'end': 1298}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99786973, 'word': 'Patras', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1308}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950677, 'word': 'Peloponnese', 'start': 1316, 'end': 1327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99770325, 'word': 'Leucas', 'start': 1340, 'end': 1346}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99699163, 'word': 'Corcyra', 'start': 1358, 'end': 1365}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9966653, 'word': 'Acroceraunia', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1388}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99693537, 'word': 'Brindisi', 'start': 1400, 'end': 1408}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9930004, 'word': 'Rome', 'start': 1420, 'end': 1424}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9881126, 'word': 'Alps', 'start': 1441, 'end': 1445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99629056, 'word': 'Scingomagum', 'start': 1464, 'end': 1475}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9877423, 'word': 'Gallia', 'start': 1489, 'end': 1495}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99149173, 'word': 'Pyrenees', 'start': 1503, 'end': 1511}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9932939, 'word': 'Illiberis', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1524}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9776768, 'word': 'Ocean', 'start': 1537, 'end': 1542}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9586628, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 1560, 'end': 1565}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99361765, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 1581, 'end': 1586}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.988962, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 1612, 'end': 1623}]"
365,7f984080-21e5-4372-b525-718d460455f8,https://topostext.org/place/38898WGan,Ganges,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:2.112.1,23.7818,89.8009,2,112,1.0,"Our own portion of the earth, which is my subject, swims as it were in the ocean by which, as we have said, it is surrounded; its longest extent is from East to West, i.e. from India to the Pillars consecrated to Hercules at Cadiz, a distance of 8,568 miles according to Artemidorus, but 9,818 according to Isidore. Artemidorus adds in addition from Cadiz round the Sacred Promontory to Artabrum promontory, the longest projection of the coast of Spain, 890 1/2 miles. The measurement runs by a double route; from the river Ganges and its mouth where it flows into the Eastern Ocean, through India and Parthyene to the Syrian city of Myriandrus situated on the Issic gulf 5,215, from there by the shortest sea-route to the island of Cyprus, from Patara in Lycia to Rhodes, to the island of Astypalaea in the Carpathian Sea, to Taenarus in Laconia, Lilybaion in Sicily, Caralis in Sardinia, 213, thence to Cadiz 1,250, the total distance from the Eastern Sea making 8,568. Another route, which is more certain, extends mainly overland from the Ganges to the river Euphrates 5,169, thence to Mazaca in Cappadocia 244, thence through Phrygia and Caria to Ephesus 499, from Ephesus across the Aegean Sea to Delos 200, to the Isthmus 202 1/2, thence by land and the Alcyonian Sea and the Gulf of Corinth to Patras in the Peloponnese 102 1/2, to Leucas 87 1/2, to Corcyra ditto, to Acroceraunia 82 1/2, to Brindisi 87 1/2, to Rome 360, across the Alps to the village of Scingomagum 518, through Gallia to the Pyrenees at Illiberis 456, to the Ocean and the coast of Spain 832, across to Cadiz 7 1/2 — which figures by Artemidorus's calculation make 8,995 miles. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7412269, 'word': 'East', 'start': 153, 'end': 157}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.77896315, 'word': 'West', 'start': 161, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9901855, 'word': 'India', 'start': 177, 'end': 182}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.981185, 'word': 'Pillars', 'start': 190, 'end': 197}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6513607, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 213, 'end': 221}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9983041, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 225, 'end': 230}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99825233, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 271, 'end': 282}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9981376, 'word': 'Isidore', 'start': 307, 'end': 314}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99760133, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 316, 'end': 327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99863917, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 350, 'end': 355}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952378, 'word': 'Sacred Promontory', 'start': 366, 'end': 383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99757296, 'word': 'Artabrum', 'start': 387, 'end': 395}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9771263, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 447, 'end': 452}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99382377, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 524, 'end': 530}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99455774, 'word': 'Eastern Ocean', 'start': 569, 'end': 582}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9964535, 'word': 'India', 'start': 592, 'end': 597}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9974421, 'word': 'Parthyene', 'start': 602, 'end': 611}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7181697, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 619, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9957962, 'word': 'Myriandrus', 'start': 634, 'end': 644}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99472, 'word': 'Issic', 'start': 661, 'end': 666}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9846884, 'word': 'Cyprus', 'start': 733, 'end': 739}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99746203, 'word': 'Patara', 'start': 746, 'end': 752}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99605405, 'word': 'Lycia', 'start': 756, 'end': 761}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950653, 'word': 'Rhodes', 'start': 765, 'end': 771}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950871, 'word': 'Astypalaea', 'start': 790, 'end': 800}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9952965, 'word': 'Carpathian Sea', 'start': 808, 'end': 822}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9977053, 'word': 'Taenarus', 'start': 827, 'end': 835}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973834, 'word': 'Laconia', 'start': 839, 'end': 846}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99835664, 'word': 'Lilybaion', 'start': 848, 'end': 857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9965731, 'word': 'Sicily', 'start': 861, 'end': 867}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9982034, 'word': 'Caralis', 'start': 869, 'end': 876}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9973908, 'word': 'Sardinia', 'start': 880, 'end': 888}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9985423, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 905, 'end': 910}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99497855, 'word': 'Eastern Sea', 'start': 946, 'end': 957}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9984516, 'word': 'Ganges', 'start': 1043, 'end': 1049}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99564904, 'word': 'Euphrates', 'start': 1063, 'end': 1072}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99918693, 'word': 'Mazaca', 'start': 1090, 'end': 1096}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.998516, 'word': 'Cappadocia', 'start': 1100, 'end': 1110}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99844235, 'word': 'Phrygia', 'start': 1131, 'end': 1138}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9980102, 'word': 'Caria', 'start': 1143, 'end': 1148}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99822694, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1152, 'end': 1159}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99890864, 'word': 'Ephesus', 'start': 1170, 'end': 1177}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99849844, 'word': 'Aegean Sea', 'start': 1189, 'end': 1199}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99842453, 'word': 'Delos', 'start': 1203, 'end': 1208}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99730116, 'word': 'Isthmus', 'start': 1221, 'end': 1228}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99797475, 'word': 'Alcyonian Sea', 'start': 1261, 'end': 1274}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9968625, 'word': 'Gulf of Corinth', 'start': 1283, 'end': 1298}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99786973, 'word': 'Patras', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1308}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9950677, 'word': 'Peloponnese', 'start': 1316, 'end': 1327}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99770325, 'word': 'Leucas', 'start': 1340, 'end': 1346}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99699163, 'word': 'Corcyra', 'start': 1358, 'end': 1365}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9966653, 'word': 'Acroceraunia', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1388}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99693537, 'word': 'Brindisi', 'start': 1400, 'end': 1408}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9930004, 'word': 'Rome', 'start': 1420, 'end': 1424}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9881126, 'word': 'Alps', 'start': 1441, 'end': 1445}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99629056, 'word': 'Scingomagum', 'start': 1464, 'end': 1475}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9877423, 'word': 'Gallia', 'start': 1489, 'end': 1495}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99149173, 'word': 'Pyrenees', 'start': 1503, 'end': 1511}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9932939, 'word': 'Illiberis', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1524}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9776768, 'word': 'Ocean', 'start': 1537, 'end': 1542}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9586628, 'word': 'Spain', 'start': 1560, 'end': 1565}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99361765, 'word': 'Cadiz', 'start': 1581, 'end': 1586}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.988962, 'word': 'Artemidorus', 'start': 1612, 'end': 1623}]"
2015,244de17e-a30b-4392-a07b-4c4fbc9cc2a0,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:4.17.4,30.0,74.0,4,17,4.0,"Such is Macedonia, which was once the mistress of the world, which once extended her career over Asia, Armenia, Iberia, Albania, Cappadocia, Syria, Egypt, Taurus, and Caucasus, which reduced the whole of the East under her power, and triumphed over the Bactri, the Medes, and the Persians. She too it was who proved the conqueror of India, thus treading in the footsteps of Father Liber and of Hercules; and this is that same Macedonia, of which our own general Paulus Aemilius sold to pillage seventy-two cities in one day. So great the difference in her lot resulting from the actions of two individuals! ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95384216, 'word': 'Macedonia', 'start': 8, 'end': 17}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99759394, 'word': 'Asia', 'start': 97, 'end': 101}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9984207, 'word': 'Armenia', 'start': 103, 'end': 110}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9981336, 'word': 'Iberia', 'start': 112, 'end': 118}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9983163, 'word': 'Albania', 'start': 120, 'end': 127}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99857116, 'word': 'Cappadocia', 'start': 129, 'end': 139}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.997771, 'word': 'Syria', 'start': 141, 'end': 146}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99775535, 'word': 'Egypt', 'start': 148, 'end': 153}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99271435, 'word': 'Taurus', 'start': 155, 'end': 161}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.992959, 'word': 'Caucasus', 'start': 167, 'end': 175}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8675513, 'word': 'East', 'start': 208, 'end': 212}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.76293546, 'word': 'Bactri', 'start': 253, 'end': 259}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.76744413, 'word': 'Medes', 'start': 265, 'end': 270}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.39279035, 'word': 'Persians', 'start': 280, 'end': 288}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97908324, 'word': 'India', 'start': 333, 'end': 338}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.71568835, 'word': 'Father Liber', 'start': 374, 'end': 386}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.9887404, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 394, 'end': 402}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9801026, 'word': 'Macedonia', 'start': 426, 'end': 435}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.99024045, 'word': 'Paulus Aemilius', 'start': 462, 'end': 477}]"
2538,f1d2eff6-24c8-4ce3-a98f-3ba088ab12b4,https://topostext.org/place/293710WAke,Acesinus,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:4.26.2,29.1513,70.7367,4,26,2.0,"At this spot begins a well-wooded district, which has given to the sea that washes its banks the name of the Hylaean Sea; its inhabitants are called Enoechadlae. Beyond them is the river Panticapes, which separates the Nomades and the Georgi, and after it the Acesinus. Some authors say that the Panticapes flows into the Borysthenes below Olbia. Others, who are more correct, say that it is the Hypanis: so great is the mistake made by those who have placed it in Asia. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99848914, 'word': 'Hylaean Sea', 'start': 109, 'end': 120}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.85208315, 'word': 'Enoechadlae', 'start': 149, 'end': 160}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9962537, 'word': 'Panticapes', 'start': 187, 'end': 197}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99729985, 'word': 'Nomades', 'start': 219, 'end': 226}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9951568, 'word': 'Georgi', 'start': 235, 'end': 241}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99572206, 'word': 'Acesinus', 'start': 260, 'end': 268}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99520594, 'word': 'Panticapes', 'start': 296, 'end': 306}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9967546, 'word': 'Borysthenes', 'start': 322, 'end': 333}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9990891, 'word': 'Olbia', 'start': 340, 'end': 345}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9772519, 'word': 'Hypanis', 'start': 396, 'end': 403}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9931618, 'word': 'Asia', 'start': 465, 'end': 469}]"
2938,dccbb057-5f16-4486-881a-967e8444ce6e,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:5.11.1,30.0,74.0,5,11,1.0,"THE CITIES OF EGYPT: Egypt, besides its boast of extreme antiquity, asserts that it contained, in the reign of King Amasis, 20,000 inhabited cities: in our day they are still very numerous, though no longer of any particular note. Still however we find the following ones mentioned as of great renown — the City of Apollo; next, that of Leucothea; then Great Diospolis, otherwise Thebes, known to fame for its hundred gates; Coptos, which from its proximity to the Nile, forms its nearest emporium for the merchandise of India and Arabia; then the city of Venus, and then another of city of Jupiter. After this comes Tentyris, below which is Abydus, the royal abode of Memnon, and famous for a temple of Osiris, which is situate in Libya, at a distance from the river of seven miles and a half. Next to it comes Ptolemais, then Panopolis, and then another city of Venus, and, on the Libyan side, Lycon, where the mountains form the boundary of the province of Thebais. On passing these, we come to the city of Mercury, Alabastron, city of Dogs, and city of Hercules already mentioned. We next come to Arsinoe, and Memphis, which has been previously mentioned; between which last and the Nome of Arsinoites, upon the Libyan side, are the towers known as the Pyramids, the Labyrinth on Lake Moeris, in the construction of which no wood was employed, and the town of Crialon. Besides these, there is one place in the interior, on the confines of Arabia, of great celebrity, the City of the Sun. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91976064, 'word': 'Egypt', 'start': 21, 'end': 26}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.8060666, 'word': 'Amasis', 'start': 116, 'end': 122}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.967531, 'word': 'City of Apollo', 'start': 307, 'end': 321}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9826623, 'word': 'Leucothea', 'start': 337, 'end': 346}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9868535, 'word': 'Great Diospolis', 'start': 353, 'end': 368}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9943479, 'word': 'Thebes', 'start': 380, 'end': 386}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9963831, 'word': 'Coptos', 'start': 425, 'end': 431}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9804955, 'word': 'Nile', 'start': 465, 'end': 469}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.89003915, 'word': 'India', 'start': 521, 'end': 526}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8938884, 'word': 'Arabia', 'start': 531, 'end': 537}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8860848, 'word': 'Venus', 'start': 556, 'end': 561}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8562041, 'word': 'Jupiter', 'start': 591, 'end': 598}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9813518, 'word': 'Tentyris', 'start': 617, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9800729, 'word': 'Abydus', 'start': 642, 'end': 648}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7124393, 'word': 'Memnon', 'start': 669, 'end': 675}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8118405, 'word': 'Osiris', 'start': 704, 'end': 710}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9769033, 'word': 'Libya', 'start': 732, 'end': 737}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98787737, 'word': 'Ptolemais', 'start': 812, 'end': 821}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98905015, 'word': 'Panopolis', 'start': 828, 'end': 837}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.90254104, 'word': 'Venus', 'start': 864, 'end': 869}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.87926775, 'word': 'Libyan', 'start': 883, 'end': 889}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9856859, 'word': 'Lycon', 'start': 896, 'end': 901}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9541275, 'word': 'Thebais', 'start': 960, 'end': 967}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.87355447, 'word': 'Mercury', 'start': 1010, 'end': 1017}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9894776, 'word': 'Alabastron', 'start': 1019, 'end': 1029}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8680517, 'word': 'Dogs', 'start': 1039, 'end': 1043}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8603096, 'word': 'Hercules', 'start': 1057, 'end': 1065}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98251814, 'word': 'Arsinoe', 'start': 1101, 'end': 1108}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9935557, 'word': 'Memphis', 'start': 1114, 'end': 1121}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95763564, 'word': 'Nome of Arsinoites', 'start': 1187, 'end': 1205}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8214746, 'word': 'Libyan', 'start': 1216, 'end': 1222}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9689873, 'word': 'Pyramids', 'start': 1257, 'end': 1265}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97491926, 'word': 'Labyrinth', 'start': 1271, 'end': 1280}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9810122, 'word': 'Lake Moeris', 'start': 1284, 'end': 1295}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95586336, 'word': 'Crialon', 'start': 1364, 'end': 1371}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9557941, 'word': 'Arabia', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1449}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9621396, 'word': 'City of the Sun', 'start': 1475, 'end': 1490}]"
4109,9f4da524-b6a5-4a5f-b606-404ead41eb03,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:6.17.2,30.0,74.0,6,17,2.0,"Joining up to Adiabene are the people formerly known as the 'Carduchi,' now the Cordueni, in front of whom the river Tigris flows: and next to them are the Pratitae, entitled the Par Odon, who hold possession of the Caspian Gates. On the other side of these gates we come to the deserts of Parthia and the mountain chain of Cithenus; and after that, the most pleasant locality of all Parthia, Choara by name. Here were two cities of the Parthians, built in former times for their protection against the people of Media, Calliope, and Issatis, the last of which stood formerly on a rock. Hecatompylos, the capital of Parthia, is distant from the Caspian Gates one hundred and thirty-three miles. In such an effectual manner is the kingdom of Parthia shut out by these passes. After leaving these gates we find the nation of the Caspii, extending as far as the shores of the Caspian, a race which has given its name to these gates as well as to the sea: on the left there is a mountainous district. Turning back from this nation to the river Cyrus, the distance is said to be two hundred and twenty miles; but if we go from that river as far down as the Caspian Gates, the distance is seven hundreds miles. In the itineraries of Alexander the Great these gates were made the central or turning point in his expeditions; the distance from the Caspian Gates to the frontier of India being there set down as fifteen thousand six hundred and eighty stadia, to the city of Bactra, commonly called Zariaspa, three thousand seven hundred, and thence to the river Jaxartes five thousand stadia. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9979361, 'word': 'Adiabene', 'start': 14, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91425073, 'word': 'Carduchi', 'start': 61, 'end': 69}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.923155, 'word': 'Cordueni', 'start': 80, 'end': 88}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9940054, 'word': 'Tigris', 'start': 117, 'end': 123}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9214789, 'word': 'Pratitae', 'start': 156, 'end': 164}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.92901415, 'word': 'Par Odon', 'start': 179, 'end': 187}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.984105, 'word': 'Caspian Gates', 'start': 216, 'end': 229}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9936085, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 290, 'end': 297}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99164164, 'word': 'Cithenus', 'start': 324, 'end': 332}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99246395, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 384, 'end': 391}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99487525, 'word': 'Choara', 'start': 393, 'end': 399}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9222571, 'word': 'Parthians', 'start': 437, 'end': 446}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97297543, 'word': 'Media', 'start': 513, 'end': 518}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9821279, 'word': 'Calliope', 'start': 520, 'end': 528}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97681534, 'word': 'Issatis', 'start': 534, 'end': 541}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9693579, 'word': 'Hecatompylos', 'start': 587, 'end': 599}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9897091, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 616, 'end': 623}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9874841, 'word': 'Caspian Gates', 'start': 645, 'end': 658}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97875684, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 741, 'end': 748}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9515352, 'word': 'Caspii', 'start': 827, 'end': 833}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9787198, 'word': 'Caspian', 'start': 873, 'end': 880}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.87890345, 'word': 'Cyrus', 'start': 1040, 'end': 1045}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9876025, 'word': 'Caspian Gates', 'start': 1152, 'end': 1165}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.97263974, 'word': 'Alexander the Great', 'start': 1227, 'end': 1246}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9841759, 'word': 'Caspian Gates', 'start': 1340, 'end': 1353}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97457314, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1373, 'end': 1378}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98345655, 'word': 'Bactra', 'start': 1466, 'end': 1472}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97211266, 'word': 'Zariaspa', 'start': 1490, 'end': 1498}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9373939, 'word': 'Jaxartes', 'start': 1554, 'end': 1562}]"
4114,7a8956f3-cfa1-46fe-9535-d2a4fded3523,https://topostext.org/place/372673WOxu,Oxus,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:6.18.1,37.1923,67.2653,6,18,1.0,"NATIONS SITUATE AROUND THE HYRCANIAN SEA: Lying to the east of the Caspii is the region known as Apavortene, in which there is a place noted for its singular fertility, called Dareium. We then come to the nations of the Tapyri, the Anariaci, the Staures, and the Hyrcani, past whose shores and beyond the river Sideris the Caspian begins to take the name of the 'Hyrcanian' Sea: on this side of that stream are also the rivers Maxeras and StratoCaucasian chain. Next comes the district of Margiane, so remarkable for its sunny climate. It is the only spot in all these regions that produces the vine, being shut in on every side by verdant and refreshing hills. This district is fifteen hundred stadia in circumference, but is rendered remarkably difficult of access by sandy deserts, which extend a distance of one hundred and twenty miles: it lies opposite to the country of Parthia, and in it Alexander founded the city of Alexandria. This place having been destroyed by the barbarians, Antiochus, the son of Seleucus, rebuilt it on the same site as a Syrian city. For, seeing that it was watered by the Margus, which passes through it, and is afterwards divided into a number of streams for the irrigation of the district of Zothale, he restored it, but preferred giving it the name of Antiochia. The circumference of this city is seventy stadia: it was to this place that Orodes conducted such of the Romans as had survived the defeat of Crassus. From the mountain heights of this district, along the range of Caucasus, the savage race of the Mardi, a free people, extends as far as the Bactri. Below the district inhabited by them, we find the nations of the Orciani, the Commori, the Berdrigae, the Harmatotropi, the Citomarae, the Comani, the Marucaei, and the Mandruani. The rivers here are the Mandrus and the Chindrus. Beyond the nations already mentioned, are the Chorasmii, the Candari, the Attasini, the Paricani, the Sarangae, the Marotiani, the Aorsi, the Gaeli, by the Greek writers called Cadusii, the Matiani, the city of Heraclea, which was founded by Alexander, but was afterwards destroyed, and rebuilt by Antiochus, and by him called Achais; the Derbices also, through the middle of whose territory the river Oxus runs, after rising in Lake Oxus, the Syrmatae, the Oxydracae, the Heniochi, the Bateni, the Saraparae, and the Bactri, whose chief city is Zariaspe, which afterwards received the name of Bactra, from the river there. This last nation lies at the back of Mount Paropanisus, over against the sources of the river Indus, and is bounded by the river Ochus. Beyond it are the Sogdiani, the town of Panda, and, at the very extremity of their territory, Alexandria, founded by Alexander the Great. At this spot are the altars which were raised by Hercules and Father Liber, as also by Cyrus, Semiramis, and Alexander; for the expeditions of all these conquerors stopped short at this region, bounded as it is by the river Jaxartes, by the Scythians known as the Silis, and by Alexander and his officers supposed to have been the Tanais. This river was crossed by Demodamas, a general of kings Seleucus and Antiochus, and whose account more particularly we have here followed. He also consecrated certain altars here to Apollo Didymaeus.  ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98975533, 'word': 'Caspii', 'start': 67, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99015105, 'word': 'Apavortene', 'start': 97, 'end': 107}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9847244, 'word': 'Dareium', 'start': 176, 'end': 183}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9424007, 'word': 'Tapyri', 'start': 220, 'end': 226}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.92662567, 'word': 'Anariaci', 'start': 232, 'end': 240}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8954924, 'word': 'Staures', 'start': 246, 'end': 253}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9241677, 'word': 'Hyrcani', 'start': 263, 'end': 270}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9737466, 'word': 'Sideris', 'start': 311, 'end': 318}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9788573, 'word': 'Caspian', 'start': 323, 'end': 330}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7090097, 'word': ""Hyrcanian ' Sea"", 'start': 363, 'end': 377}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97994393, 'word': 'Maxeras', 'start': 427, 'end': 434}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9780828, 'word': 'StratoCaucasian', 'start': 439, 'end': 454}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9758354, 'word': 'Margiane', 'start': 489, 'end': 497}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95928556, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 877, 'end': 884}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.6076918, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 896, 'end': 905}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96751314, 'word': 'Alexandria', 'start': 926, 'end': 936}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.95591944, 'word': 'Antiochus', 'start': 990, 'end': 999}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.916216, 'word': 'Seleucus', 'start': 1012, 'end': 1020}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5194504, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 1055, 'end': 1061}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9875086, 'word': 'Margus', 'start': 1107, 'end': 1113}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9690317, 'word': 'Zothale', 'start': 1229, 'end': 1236}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.980753, 'word': 'Antiochia', 'start': 1290, 'end': 1299}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.676754, 'word': 'Orodes', 'start': 1377, 'end': 1383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.58814245, 'word': 'Romans', 'start': 1406, 'end': 1412}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91236633, 'word': 'Crassus', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1450}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9489612, 'word': 'Caucasus', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1523}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.90977937, 'word': 'Mardi', 'start': 1548, 'end': 1553}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.88981026, 'word': 'Bactri', 'start': 1592, 'end': 1598}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9074865, 'word': 'Orciani', 'start': 1665, 'end': 1672}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9369053, 'word': 'Commori', 'start': 1678, 'end': 1685}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9594134, 'word': 'Berdrigae', 'start': 1691, 'end': 1700}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9667007, 'word': 'Harmatotropi', 'start': 1706, 'end': 1718}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9639786, 'word': 'Citomarae', 'start': 1724, 'end': 1733}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97190934, 'word': 'Comani', 'start': 1739, 'end': 1745}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97163796, 'word': 'Marucaei', 'start': 1751, 'end': 1759}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9632143, 'word': 'Mandruani', 'start': 1769, 'end': 1778}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9536301, 'word': 'Mandrus', 'start': 1804, 'end': 1811}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95262814, 'word': 'Chindrus', 'start': 1820, 'end': 1828}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.92438775, 'word': 'Chorasmii', 'start': 1876, 'end': 1885}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9390787, 'word': 'Candari', 'start': 1891, 'end': 1898}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9187493, 'word': 'Attasini', 'start': 1904, 'end': 1912}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9089476, 'word': 'Paricani', 'start': 1918, 'end': 1926}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8990482, 'word': 'Sarangae', 'start': 1932, 'end': 1940}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9170007, 'word': 'Marotiani', 'start': 1946, 'end': 1955}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9159896, 'word': 'Aorsi', 'start': 1961, 'end': 1966}]"
4115,da0fc4bf-17a3-4e0a-b64e-2c446508fd81,https://topostext.org/place/254683WInd,Indus,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:6.18.1,25.4487,68.3192,6,18,1.0,"NATIONS SITUATE AROUND THE HYRCANIAN SEA: Lying to the east of the Caspii is the region known as Apavortene, in which there is a place noted for its singular fertility, called Dareium. We then come to the nations of the Tapyri, the Anariaci, the Staures, and the Hyrcani, past whose shores and beyond the river Sideris the Caspian begins to take the name of the 'Hyrcanian' Sea: on this side of that stream are also the rivers Maxeras and StratoCaucasian chain. Next comes the district of Margiane, so remarkable for its sunny climate. It is the only spot in all these regions that produces the vine, being shut in on every side by verdant and refreshing hills. This district is fifteen hundred stadia in circumference, but is rendered remarkably difficult of access by sandy deserts, which extend a distance of one hundred and twenty miles: it lies opposite to the country of Parthia, and in it Alexander founded the city of Alexandria. This place having been destroyed by the barbarians, Antiochus, the son of Seleucus, rebuilt it on the same site as a Syrian city. For, seeing that it was watered by the Margus, which passes through it, and is afterwards divided into a number of streams for the irrigation of the district of Zothale, he restored it, but preferred giving it the name of Antiochia. The circumference of this city is seventy stadia: it was to this place that Orodes conducted such of the Romans as had survived the defeat of Crassus. From the mountain heights of this district, along the range of Caucasus, the savage race of the Mardi, a free people, extends as far as the Bactri. Below the district inhabited by them, we find the nations of the Orciani, the Commori, the Berdrigae, the Harmatotropi, the Citomarae, the Comani, the Marucaei, and the Mandruani. The rivers here are the Mandrus and the Chindrus. Beyond the nations already mentioned, are the Chorasmii, the Candari, the Attasini, the Paricani, the Sarangae, the Marotiani, the Aorsi, the Gaeli, by the Greek writers called Cadusii, the Matiani, the city of Heraclea, which was founded by Alexander, but was afterwards destroyed, and rebuilt by Antiochus, and by him called Achais; the Derbices also, through the middle of whose territory the river Oxus runs, after rising in Lake Oxus, the Syrmatae, the Oxydracae, the Heniochi, the Bateni, the Saraparae, and the Bactri, whose chief city is Zariaspe, which afterwards received the name of Bactra, from the river there. This last nation lies at the back of Mount Paropanisus, over against the sources of the river Indus, and is bounded by the river Ochus. Beyond it are the Sogdiani, the town of Panda, and, at the very extremity of their territory, Alexandria, founded by Alexander the Great. At this spot are the altars which were raised by Hercules and Father Liber, as also by Cyrus, Semiramis, and Alexander; for the expeditions of all these conquerors stopped short at this region, bounded as it is by the river Jaxartes, by the Scythians known as the Silis, and by Alexander and his officers supposed to have been the Tanais. This river was crossed by Demodamas, a general of kings Seleucus and Antiochus, and whose account more particularly we have here followed. He also consecrated certain altars here to Apollo Didymaeus.  ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98975533, 'word': 'Caspii', 'start': 67, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.99015105, 'word': 'Apavortene', 'start': 97, 'end': 107}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9847244, 'word': 'Dareium', 'start': 176, 'end': 183}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9424007, 'word': 'Tapyri', 'start': 220, 'end': 226}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.92662567, 'word': 'Anariaci', 'start': 232, 'end': 240}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8954924, 'word': 'Staures', 'start': 246, 'end': 253}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9241677, 'word': 'Hyrcani', 'start': 263, 'end': 270}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9737466, 'word': 'Sideris', 'start': 311, 'end': 318}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9788573, 'word': 'Caspian', 'start': 323, 'end': 330}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7090097, 'word': ""Hyrcanian ' Sea"", 'start': 363, 'end': 377}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97994393, 'word': 'Maxeras', 'start': 427, 'end': 434}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9780828, 'word': 'StratoCaucasian', 'start': 439, 'end': 454}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9758354, 'word': 'Margiane', 'start': 489, 'end': 497}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95928556, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 877, 'end': 884}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.6076918, 'word': 'Alexander', 'start': 896, 'end': 905}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.96751314, 'word': 'Alexandria', 'start': 926, 'end': 936}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.95591944, 'word': 'Antiochus', 'start': 990, 'end': 999}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.916216, 'word': 'Seleucus', 'start': 1012, 'end': 1020}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.5194504, 'word': 'Syrian', 'start': 1055, 'end': 1061}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9875086, 'word': 'Margus', 'start': 1107, 'end': 1113}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9690317, 'word': 'Zothale', 'start': 1229, 'end': 1236}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.980753, 'word': 'Antiochia', 'start': 1290, 'end': 1299}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.676754, 'word': 'Orodes', 'start': 1377, 'end': 1383}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.58814245, 'word': 'Romans', 'start': 1406, 'end': 1412}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91236633, 'word': 'Crassus', 'start': 1443, 'end': 1450}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9489612, 'word': 'Caucasus', 'start': 1515, 'end': 1523}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.90977937, 'word': 'Mardi', 'start': 1548, 'end': 1553}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.88981026, 'word': 'Bactri', 'start': 1592, 'end': 1598}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9074865, 'word': 'Orciani', 'start': 1665, 'end': 1672}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9369053, 'word': 'Commori', 'start': 1678, 'end': 1685}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9594134, 'word': 'Berdrigae', 'start': 1691, 'end': 1700}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9667007, 'word': 'Harmatotropi', 'start': 1706, 'end': 1718}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9639786, 'word': 'Citomarae', 'start': 1724, 'end': 1733}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97190934, 'word': 'Comani', 'start': 1739, 'end': 1745}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.97163796, 'word': 'Marucaei', 'start': 1751, 'end': 1759}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9632143, 'word': 'Mandruani', 'start': 1769, 'end': 1778}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9536301, 'word': 'Mandrus', 'start': 1804, 'end': 1811}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95262814, 'word': 'Chindrus', 'start': 1820, 'end': 1828}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.92438775, 'word': 'Chorasmii', 'start': 1876, 'end': 1885}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9390787, 'word': 'Candari', 'start': 1891, 'end': 1898}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9187493, 'word': 'Attasini', 'start': 1904, 'end': 1912}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9089476, 'word': 'Paricani', 'start': 1918, 'end': 1926}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8990482, 'word': 'Sarangae', 'start': 1932, 'end': 1940}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9170007, 'word': 'Marotiani', 'start': 1946, 'end': 1955}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9159896, 'word': 'Aorsi', 'start': 1961, 'end': 1966}]"
4121,45859f8c-2154-46f7-9a4c-f138c422e55f,https://topostext.org/place/300740RInd,India,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:6.19.1,30.0,74.0,6,19,1.0,"THE NATIONS OF SCYTHIA AND THE COUNTRIES ON THE EASTERN OCEAN. Beyond this river are the peoples of Scythia. The Persians have called them by the general name of Sacae, which properly belongs to only the nearest nation of them. The more ancient writers give them the name of Aramii. The Scythians themselves give the name of ""Chorsari"" to the Persians, and they call Mount Caucasus Graucasis, which means ""white with snow."" The multitude of these Scythian nations is quite innumerable: in their life and habits they much resemble the people of Parthia. The tribes among them that are better known are the Sacae, the Massagetae, the Dahae, the Essedones, the Ariacae, the Rhymmici, the Paesici, the Amardi, the Histi, the Edones, the Came, the Camacae, the Euchatae, the Cotieri, the Anthusiani, the Psacae, the Arimaspi, the Antacati, the Chroasai, and the Oetei; among them the Napaei are said to have been destroyed by the Palaei. The rivers in their country that are the best known, are the Mandragaeus and the Carpasus. Indeed upon no subject that I know of are there greater discrepancies among writers, from the circumstance, I suppose, of these nations being so extremely numerous, and of such migratory habits. Alexander the Great has left it stated that the water of this sea is fresh, and M. Varro informs us, that some of it, of a similar character, was brought to Pompey, when holding the chief command in the Mithridatic war in its vicinity; the salt, no doubt, being overpowered by the volume of water discharged by the rivers which flow into it. He adds also, that under the direction of Pompey, it was ascertained that it is seven days' journey from India to the river Icarus, in the country of the Bactri, which discharges itself into the Oxus, and that the merchandize of India being conveyed from it through the Caspian Sea into the Cyrus, may be brought by land to Phasis in Pontus, in five days at most. There are numerous islands throughout the whole of the Caspian sea: the only one that is well known is that of Tazata. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9219766, 'word': 'Scythia', 'start': 100, 'end': 107}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.7163824, 'word': 'Persians', 'start': 113, 'end': 121}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7857047, 'word': 'Sacae', 'start': 162, 'end': 167}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8461255, 'word': 'Aramii', 'start': 275, 'end': 281}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.47933817, 'word': 'Scythians', 'start': 287, 'end': 296}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8403425, 'word': 'Chorsari', 'start': 326, 'end': 334}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.7122468, 'word': 'Persians', 'start': 343, 'end': 351}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8840363, 'word': 'Mount Caucasus Graucasis', 'start': 367, 'end': 391}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.77268684, 'word': 'Scythian', 'start': 447, 'end': 455}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.94999987, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 544, 'end': 551}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.75232595, 'word': 'Sacae', 'start': 605, 'end': 610}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.82100624, 'word': 'Massagetae', 'start': 616, 'end': 626}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8175044, 'word': 'Dahae', 'start': 632, 'end': 637}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6909819, 'word': 'Essedones', 'start': 643, 'end': 652}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.80896264, 'word': 'Ariacae', 'start': 658, 'end': 665}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8064346, 'word': 'Rhymmici', 'start': 671, 'end': 679}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8098455, 'word': 'Paesici', 'start': 685, 'end': 692}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8061195, 'word': 'Amardi', 'start': 698, 'end': 704}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.81057316, 'word': 'Histi', 'start': 710, 'end': 715}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8791431, 'word': 'Edones', 'start': 721, 'end': 727}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8581071, 'word': 'Came', 'start': 733, 'end': 737}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91392654, 'word': 'Camacae', 'start': 743, 'end': 750}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8973085, 'word': 'Euchatae', 'start': 756, 'end': 764}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8616098, 'word': 'Cotieri', 'start': 770, 'end': 777}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.86626786, 'word': 'Anthusiani', 'start': 783, 'end': 793}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.81770635, 'word': 'Psacae', 'start': 799, 'end': 805}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.85353285, 'word': 'Arimaspi', 'start': 811, 'end': 819}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.864273, 'word': 'Antacati', 'start': 825, 'end': 833}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8692477, 'word': 'Chroasai', 'start': 839, 'end': 847}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.85888493, 'word': 'Oetei', 'start': 857, 'end': 862}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9103554, 'word': 'Napaei', 'start': 879, 'end': 885}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8118177, 'word': 'Palaei', 'start': 925, 'end': 931}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98736066, 'word': 'Mandragaeus', 'start': 994, 'end': 1005}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9895829, 'word': 'Carpasus', 'start': 1014, 'end': 1022}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.97548914, 'word': 'Alexander the Great', 'start': 1219, 'end': 1238}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.8321084, 'word': 'M', 'start': 1299, 'end': 1300}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.93409944, 'word': 'Varro', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1307}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.45966536, 'word': 'Pompey', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1382}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.666183, 'word': 'Mithridatic war', 'start': 1422, 'end': 1437}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.69290096, 'word': 'Pompey', 'start': 1603, 'end': 1609}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9463721, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1666, 'end': 1671}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.76886606, 'word': 'Icarus', 'start': 1685, 'end': 1691}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8817885, 'word': 'Bactri', 'start': 1715, 'end': 1721}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9388766, 'word': 'Oxus', 'start': 1756, 'end': 1760}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9327435, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1790, 'end': 1795}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9554795, 'word': 'Caspian Sea', 'start': 1831, 'end': 1842}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7968555, 'word': 'Cyrus', 'start': 1852, 'end': 1857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8907886, 'word': 'Phasis', 'start': 1885, 'end': 1891}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95266813, 'word': 'Pontus', 'start': 1895, 'end': 1901}]"
4122,7de171b0-353e-4b6f-a7b5-86582d25e793,https://topostext.org/place/372673WOxu,Oxus,urn:cts:latinLit:phi0978.phi001:6.19.1,37.1923,67.2653,6,19,1.0,"THE NATIONS OF SCYTHIA AND THE COUNTRIES ON THE EASTERN OCEAN. Beyond this river are the peoples of Scythia. The Persians have called them by the general name of Sacae, which properly belongs to only the nearest nation of them. The more ancient writers give them the name of Aramii. The Scythians themselves give the name of ""Chorsari"" to the Persians, and they call Mount Caucasus Graucasis, which means ""white with snow."" The multitude of these Scythian nations is quite innumerable: in their life and habits they much resemble the people of Parthia. The tribes among them that are better known are the Sacae, the Massagetae, the Dahae, the Essedones, the Ariacae, the Rhymmici, the Paesici, the Amardi, the Histi, the Edones, the Came, the Camacae, the Euchatae, the Cotieri, the Anthusiani, the Psacae, the Arimaspi, the Antacati, the Chroasai, and the Oetei; among them the Napaei are said to have been destroyed by the Palaei. The rivers in their country that are the best known, are the Mandragaeus and the Carpasus. Indeed upon no subject that I know of are there greater discrepancies among writers, from the circumstance, I suppose, of these nations being so extremely numerous, and of such migratory habits. Alexander the Great has left it stated that the water of this sea is fresh, and M. Varro informs us, that some of it, of a similar character, was brought to Pompey, when holding the chief command in the Mithridatic war in its vicinity; the salt, no doubt, being overpowered by the volume of water discharged by the rivers which flow into it. He adds also, that under the direction of Pompey, it was ascertained that it is seven days' journey from India to the river Icarus, in the country of the Bactri, which discharges itself into the Oxus, and that the merchandize of India being conveyed from it through the Caspian Sea into the Cyrus, may be brought by land to Phasis in Pontus, in five days at most. There are numerous islands throughout the whole of the Caspian sea: the only one that is well known is that of Tazata. ","[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9219766, 'word': 'Scythia', 'start': 100, 'end': 107}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.7163824, 'word': 'Persians', 'start': 113, 'end': 121}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7857047, 'word': 'Sacae', 'start': 162, 'end': 167}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8461255, 'word': 'Aramii', 'start': 275, 'end': 281}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.47933817, 'word': 'Scythians', 'start': 287, 'end': 296}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8403425, 'word': 'Chorsari', 'start': 326, 'end': 334}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.7122468, 'word': 'Persians', 'start': 343, 'end': 351}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8840363, 'word': 'Mount Caucasus Graucasis', 'start': 367, 'end': 391}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.77268684, 'word': 'Scythian', 'start': 447, 'end': 455}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.94999987, 'word': 'Parthia', 'start': 544, 'end': 551}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.75232595, 'word': 'Sacae', 'start': 605, 'end': 610}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.82100624, 'word': 'Massagetae', 'start': 616, 'end': 626}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8175044, 'word': 'Dahae', 'start': 632, 'end': 637}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.6909819, 'word': 'Essedones', 'start': 643, 'end': 652}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.80896264, 'word': 'Ariacae', 'start': 658, 'end': 665}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8064346, 'word': 'Rhymmici', 'start': 671, 'end': 679}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8098455, 'word': 'Paesici', 'start': 685, 'end': 692}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8061195, 'word': 'Amardi', 'start': 698, 'end': 704}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.81057316, 'word': 'Histi', 'start': 710, 'end': 715}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8791431, 'word': 'Edones', 'start': 721, 'end': 727}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8581071, 'word': 'Came', 'start': 733, 'end': 737}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.91392654, 'word': 'Camacae', 'start': 743, 'end': 750}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8973085, 'word': 'Euchatae', 'start': 756, 'end': 764}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8616098, 'word': 'Cotieri', 'start': 770, 'end': 777}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.86626786, 'word': 'Anthusiani', 'start': 783, 'end': 793}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.81770635, 'word': 'Psacae', 'start': 799, 'end': 805}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.85353285, 'word': 'Arimaspi', 'start': 811, 'end': 819}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.864273, 'word': 'Antacati', 'start': 825, 'end': 833}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8692477, 'word': 'Chroasai', 'start': 839, 'end': 847}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.85888493, 'word': 'Oetei', 'start': 857, 'end': 862}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9103554, 'word': 'Napaei', 'start': 879, 'end': 885}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8118177, 'word': 'Palaei', 'start': 925, 'end': 931}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.98736066, 'word': 'Mandragaeus', 'start': 994, 'end': 1005}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9895829, 'word': 'Carpasus', 'start': 1014, 'end': 1022}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.97548914, 'word': 'Alexander the Great', 'start': 1219, 'end': 1238}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.8321084, 'word': 'M', 'start': 1299, 'end': 1300}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': 0.93409944, 'word': 'Varro', 'start': 1302, 'end': 1307}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.45966536, 'word': 'Pompey', 'start': 1376, 'end': 1382}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': 0.666183, 'word': 'Mithridatic war', 'start': 1422, 'end': 1437}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.69290096, 'word': 'Pompey', 'start': 1603, 'end': 1609}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9463721, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1666, 'end': 1671}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.76886606, 'word': 'Icarus', 'start': 1685, 'end': 1691}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8817885, 'word': 'Bactri', 'start': 1715, 'end': 1721}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9388766, 'word': 'Oxus', 'start': 1756, 'end': 1760}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9327435, 'word': 'India', 'start': 1790, 'end': 1795}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.9554795, 'word': 'Caspian Sea', 'start': 1831, 'end': 1842}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.7968555, 'word': 'Cyrus', 'start': 1852, 'end': 1857}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.8907886, 'word': 'Phasis', 'start': 1885, 'end': 1891}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': 0.95266813, 'word': 'Pontus', 'start': 1895, 'end': 1901}]"
